Guide to the Frank J. Donner Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Writings, 1950-1992; Series IV
  - Books
    - Protectors of Privilege
      - Promotional materials, 1990-1992 (Box 62, Folder 86)
      - Reviews, 1990-1991 (Box 62, Folder 87)
    - "Exploring the Wreckage"
      - Correspondence [primarily fundraising; includes book proposal], 1989-1991 (Box 63, Folder 88)
      - Manuscripts
        - Outline, Circa 1990 (Box 63, Folder 89)
        - "Deregulation", Circa 1990 (Box 63, Folder 90)
        - "Ellingwood", Circa 1990 (Box 63, Folder 91)
        - "The Ministry of Secrecy and Deception", Circa 1990 (Box 63, Folder 92)
        - "Nicaragua Revisited", Circa 1990 (Box 63, Folder 93)
        - "Notes on the Joan Claybrook Book", Circa 1990 (Box 63, Folder 94)
        - "Sanctuary Conspiracy Trial", Circa 1990 (Box 63, Folder 95)
        - "White House Uber Alles", Circa 1990 (Box 63, Folder 96)
      - Notes and fragments, Circa 1990 (Box 63, Folder 97-98)
  - Civil Liberties Reporter [edited by Donner], 1950-1952 (Box 63, Folder 99)
  - Letters published in newspapers and magazines [includes the "Donner/Francis letters," published in The Nation ], 1966,1968, 1982 (Box 63, Folder 100-101)
  - Notes
    - "Important notes", undated (Box 64, Folder 102-103)
    - Abortion in the Bush administration, 1991, undated (Box 64, Folder 104)
    - Aseff the Spy [book published by Boris Nikolajewsky], undated (Box 64, Folder 105)
    - Bebel, August, undated (Box 64, Folder 106)
    - Blacklists, undated (Box 64, Folder 107)
    - Boland amendment, undated (Box 64, Folder 108)
    - Civil rights, undated (Box 64, Folder 109)
    - Compulsory disclosure, undated (Box 64, Folder 110)
    - "Defenses and Sanctions", undated (Box 64, Folder 111)
    - "Emergence of a Fascist Pattern", undated (Box 64, Folder 112)
    - Free speech cases, undated (Box 64, Folder 113 - 116)
    - Haig, Alexander, undated (Box 64, Folder 117)
    - Informers, undated (Box 64, Folder 118)
    - Labor, undated (Box 64, Folder 119)
    - Labor spies, undated (Box 64, Folder 120)
    - Libya, undated (Box 64, Folder 121)
    - Lives of Twelve Bad Men, undated (Box 64, Folder 122)
    - "The Police and the Informant" [thesis by Michael McCann], undated (Box 64, Folder 123)
    - Provocateurs, undated (Box 64, Folder 124)
    - Quayle and McCarthyism, undated (Box 64, Folder 125)
    - Racism, undated (Box 64, Folder 126)
    - Reagan, Ronald, undated (Box 64, Folder 127-131)
    - Separation of church and state, undated (Box 64, Folder 132)
    - Separation of powers, undated (Box 64, Folder 133)
    - Surveillance, undated (Box 64, Folder 134)
    - Undercover agents, undated (Box 64, Folder 135)
    - Note cards (miscellaneous), undated (Box 65)
  - Speeches
    - "The American Right Wing", 1961 (Box 66, Folder 136)
    - "Political Intelligence: Cameras, Informers, and Files", 1974 (Box 66, Folder 137)
    - "Master II" [speech for the ACLU], 1980s (Box 66, Folder 138)
    - Unidentified and untitled, undated (Box 66, Folder 139-140)
  - Writings of Others
    - Behrstock, Julian. "A Memoir of Dissent: McCarthyism at the UN", 1992 (Box 67, Folder 141)
    - Bellanti, Russ. "Old Nazis, the New Right and the Reagan Administration: The Role of Domestic Fascist Networks in the Republican Party and Their Effect on U.S. Cold War Politics", 1988 (Box 67, Folder 142)
    - Boresage, Robert. "Entrapment: The Defense Against Police Solicitation", undated (Box 67, Folder 143)
    - Brownell, Herbert. "The Fight Against Communism" [a report to the nation], 1954 (Box 67, Folder 144)
    - Buchner, Johannes. "The Agent Provocateur in the Labour Movement", undated (Box 67, Folder 145)
    - Cain, Harry P. "Strong in Their Pride and Free", 1955 (Box 67, Folder 146)
    - Carpenter, Ted Galen. "Police State Vanguard: America's Burgeoning Informer System", 1985 (Box 67, Folder 147)
    - Davis, Elmer. "Must We Mislead the Public?", 1951 (Box 67, Folder 148)
    - Ellsworth, Ralph E. and Sarah M. Harris. "The American Right Wing", 1960 (Box 67, Folder 149)
    - French, Richard. "The Politics of the Word: Meaning as Power on the Religious Right", 1981 (Box 67, Folder 150)
    - Goldstein, Robert J. "An American Gulag: The Story of Summary, Arrest, and Emergency Retention of Political Dissidents in the United States", undated (Box 67, Folder 151)
    - Green, Gil [personal account of McCarthy era], undated (Box 67, Folder 152)
    - Karmen, Andy. "Agent Provocateurs: A Growing Threat to the Movement", undated (Box 67, Folder 153)
    - Kelly, Daniel [untitled manuscript re: FBI and DEA reorganization], undated (Box 67, Folder 154)
    - Lacovara, Phillip A. "Presidential Power to Gather Intelligence: The Tension Between Article II and Amendment IV", undated (Box 67, Folder 155)
    - Landis, Frederick S. [untitled manuscript re: CIA relationship with the press], 1978 (Box 67, Folder 156)
    - Lerner, Michael, Laurie Zoloth, and Wilson Riles, Jr. "Bringing It All Back Home: A Strategy to Deal with the Radical Right", Circa 1981 (Box 67, Folder 157)
    - MacKenzie, Angus. "CIA Domestic Operations", undated (Box 67, Folder 158)
    - Matson, John. "Control of Police Informants in Peace Groups", 1968 (Box 67, Folder 159)
    - McGrath, J. Howard. "Remarks at the Advertising Club of New York", 1950 (Box 67, Folder 160)
    - Petchesky, Rosalind. "Anti-Abortion, Anti-Feminism, and the Rise of the New Right'", 1981 (Box 67, Folder 161)
    - Peterzell, [Jay]. "Gray, Felt, and Miller: The Demon of Influence'", 1978 (Box 67, Folder 162)
    - Shattuck, John H. "Political Surveillance: Stigmatizing the First Amendment", undated (Box 67, Folder 163)
    - Shields, Art. "Provocateurs Against the People", 1972 (Box 67, Folder 164)
    - Suall, Irwin. "The American Ultras: The Extreme Right and the Military Industrial Complex", 1962 (Box 67, Folder 165)
    - Tomkins, William F. "Security Problems Facing the U.S. and the Administration'' Program", 1954 (Box 67, Folder 166)
- Additional Material, Accession 2003-M-016
  The accession consists of research materials, drafts, and notes for Frank Donner's unpublished book: "Exploring the Wreckage: The Damage Inflicted by Reaganism To Our Democratic Heritage."
  - Topical Files
    - Abortion (Box 1)
    - Iran/Contra (Box 1)
    - Separation of Powers (Box 1)
    - Acker, William N. (Box 1)
    - War Powers (Box 1)
    - "Uber Alles" (Box 1)
    - Special Prosecutor (Box 2)
    - Church and state (Box 2)
    - Abortion gag rule (Box 2)
    - Pornography (Box 2)
    - Bush, George Herbert Walker (Box 2)
    - Abortion (Box 3)
    - Surveillance and censorship (Box 3)
    - U.S. Postal Service (Box 3)
    - OMB Watch (Box 3)
    - OMB/OSHA (Box 3)
    - Reagan court appointments (Box 3)
    - Ethics violations of Reagan staff (Box 4)
    - Michael Deaver and Lyn Nofziger (Box 4)
    - Newt Gingrich (Box 4)
    - Reagan court appointments (Box 4)
    - Rehnquist and Scalia (Box 4)
    - Department of Housing and Urban Development (Box 4)
    - Department of Health and Human Services (Box 4)
    - Meese, Edwin (Box 4)
    - Bush court appointments (Box 4)
    - Scalia, Antonin (Box 5)
    - Wright, Jim (Box 5)
    - "Uber Alles Post-election" (Box 5)
    - White House Office of Management and Budget (Box 5)
    - Legal Services Corporation (Box 5)
    - Nuclear Regulatory Commission (Box 5)
    - Center for Investigative Journalism, Inc. (Box 5)
    - Center for National Security Studies (Box 5)
    - "Star Wars" missile defense system (Box 5)
    - Consumer Product Safety Commission (Box 6)
    - Occupational Safety and Health Administration (Box 6)
    - Environmental Protection Agency (Box 6)
    - White House Office of Management and Budget (Box 6)
    - Nuclear Regulatory Commission (Box 6)
    - Legal Services Corporation (Box 6)
    - Buchanan, Patrick (Box 6)
    - National Archives (Box 6)
    - Judicial appointments (Box 7)
    - National Endowment for Democracy (Box 7)
    - Wick, Charlie (Box 7)
    - Race issues (Box 7)
    - Foreign Service (Box 7)
    - Bennett, James (Box 7)
  - Drafts, notes, and chapters (Box 8–11)
  - Audiotapes, floppy discs, and note cards (Box 12)
    The material is unprocessed and may contain sensitive information or be in a physical state that would prohibit use. Researchers wishing to request access should email mssa.assist@yale.edu requesting specific box numbers in order to initiate the review process, which may take several weeks.